The Alan Moore Transcription Project presents:

CROSS, STAR, MOON, SHAPES IN THE SAND ( EVERYTHING GOES WRONG )

(comic strip from Promethea #24, February 2003)

(C) 2003 America's Best Comics, LLC

(transcription made from the original comic)

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

HEADING: PROmEThEA

CAPTION: God-fostered child made living tale that the imaginative might put on like pearls, or armor. So the story went.

CAPTION: They spoke it in Arabic, where a girl was moved to pen her own song of Promethea, and, doing so, became the heroine.

CAPTION: They told it in Constantinople and inspired a maid to verse so that she was alike transformed, made to manifest fable.

CAPTION: In her eastern wastes, after a time, Promethea heard the Prophet's teachings and, renouncing her Pagan idols, was made convert.

CAPTION: In her northern city likewise did Promethea set aside all magic art, and so did enter into Christ.

CAPTION: And nether one knew of the other. Wind drew serpent-trails between the dunes. In this way, many years were passed.

ON POSTER: GLOWORMS

SOPHIE: UMMMM.

SOPHIE: HUH.

SOPHIE (SINGS): ...BEAT ME LIKE AN EGG BY FABERGE...

SOPHIE (SINGS): ...LA DA DA DA...

SOPHIE: HEY, MOM.

SOPHIE: GOD, I SLEPT GREAT LAST NIGHT. IT'S SO GOOD BEING BACK HOME, WITH YOU AND EVERYTHING.

TRISH: BABY, I HARDLY SLEPT. I WAS THINKING, ABOUT EVERYTHING YOU TOLD ME. EVERYTHING WE TALKED ABOUT.

TRISH: COME ON AND EAT YOUR ACHOCALYPSE POPS.

TRISH: I STILL CAN'T GET OVER IT. YOU BEING PROMETHEA.

TRISH: THAT STUFF...YOU KNOW. ABOUT YOUR DAD. WE GOTTA TALK MORE ABOUT THAT.

SOPHIE: -MNMF- YEAH, WE DO. THERE'S A LOT OF THINGS WE HAVE TO DO TOGETHER.

SOPHIE: MOM, LOOK, I'D BETTER GET TO COLLEGE...

HEADING: CROSS, STAR, MOON, SHAPES IN THE SAND ( EVERYTHING GOES WRONG )

CREDITS: ALAN MOORE, writer  co-creators  J.H. WILLIAMS III, pencils/painter  MICK GRAY, inker  JEROMY COX, colors  TODD KLEIN, letters  KRISTY QUINN, asst. ed.  SCOTT DUNBIER, editor

TRISH: I KNOW, SWEETHEART. THIS PROMETHEA THING, IT'S GREAT, BUT IT AIN'T A FUTURE.

TRISH: YOU DON'T WANT IT SCREWING UP YOUR GRADES.

SOPHIE: HA HA. MOM, I'M KINDA KNOCKED OUT THAT YOU CARE SO MUCH.

SOPHIE: I'LL BE BACK LATER, AND WE'LL TALK.

SOPHIE: AND MOM, THIS IS SORT OF SECRET, OKAY? ONLY YOU AND STACIA KNOW ABOUT THIS.

SOPHIE: LISTEN, I'LL SEE YOU LATER. I LOVE YOU.

TRISH: I LOVE YOU, BABY.

ON BUILDING: L13

ON VEHICLE: SKYBUS

ON SIGN: BUS 17

ON SIGN: TR-

ON NEWSPAPER: MY WORD  NEED LOVE? CALL 1-9-  NEW YORK TIMELINE CASCADE AHEAD IN MAYORAL RACE

ON VEHICLE: 17  17

ON STRUCTURE: 17  TRANSIT

ON BILLBOARD: WHAT HURT ME MOST, THOUGH,WAS THE PAIN.  Weeping gorilla COMIX

ON VEHICLE: 17

ON BUILDING: SCHOOL  OF E-

SOPHIE: HEY.

?: HEY, SOPHIE.

ON WALL: 32-

ON CLOTHING: 1

ON CLOTHING: N

SOPHIE: STACE!

ON WALL: 319

SOPHIE: OH MAN, IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE YOU!

SOPHIE: WAIT TILL I TELL YOU ALL THE COOL PLACES I'VE BEEN!

SOPHIE: IT WAS FANTASTIC! I MET MY DAD, MY REAL DAD? STACE, HE WAS GORGEOUS!

SOPHIE: AND THERE WAS THIS SCARY BIT, WHERE I SAW GRACE AND YOU. YOU WERE...

SOPHIE: UH...

ON CLOTHING: -C

ON CLOTHING: thE BLOW mEez

SOPHIE: STACIA?

SOPHIE: HEY.

SOPHIE: HEY, COME ON. WHAT'S UP? DID I DO SOMETHING?

SOPHIE: STACE, COME ON, PLEASE. THIS IS SCARING ME.

ON CLOTHING: -O-  -U-

STACIA: OH. NOBODY ARRANGED A WELCOME HOME PARTY FOR SOPHIE, AND IT'S SCARING HER.

STACIA: WHEREAS ME AND GRACE HANDLING THAT DEMON-COCKTAIL OF A MAYOR, THAT WAS JUST R&R, HUH?

SOPHIE: STACE?

SOPHIE: L-LOOK, I'M BACK, OKAY? I CAN TAKE OVER AS PROMETHEA AGAIN...

STACIA: YOU THINK? WHAT, BEING PROMETHEA'S SOMETHING YOU CAN JUST HAND OUT OR TAKE AWAY?

STACIA: SO, SOPHIE, THIS KABALLAH: DID YOU MEET GOD? GIVE HIM ANY GOOD ADVICE?

SOPHIE: STACIA, WHY ARE YOU BEING LIKE THIS? WAS...WAS IT TOUGH, BEING PARTNERED WITH GRACE?

STACIA: JESUS, SOPHIE, YOU ARE SO NAIVE.

STACIA: I'M £$%&ING GRACE.

STACIA: WE LOVE EACH OTHER.

STACIA: AND WE'RE STAYING TOGETHER.

STACIA: WHICH MEANS I'M STAYING ON AS PROMETHEA. END OF STORY.

STACIA (OFF PANEL): SEE YOU AROUND.

SOPHIE: HEY! HEY! DON'T YOU JUST WALK OFF!

SOPHIE: STACIA, DON'T YOU £$%&ING DARE!

STACIA: YOU GOT ABOUT ONE SECOND TO GET YOUR £$%&ING HAND OFF ME, BITCH.

SOPHIE: OR WHAT? HUH?

SOPHIE: STACIA, YOU'RE LIKE SOME LITTLE KID. YOU'VE GOT NO IDEA. I'VE BEEN APPOINTED PROMETHEA BY THE HIGHEST POWER THERE IS!

SOPHIE: AND WHAT, YOU THINK JUST BECAUSE YOU'VE GOT YOUR DYKEY LITTLE CRUSH ON GRACE, ALL THAT CHANGES? YOU THINK...

SFX: SPAP!

?: WHAT HAPPENED? I DIDN'T SEE...

?: VANDERVEER. SHE JUST HIT THE OTHER GIRL.

?: THEY'RE JUST A COUPLE O' LEZZES. THEY PROBABLY...

?: WHOAA...

STACIA: AAA!

SOPHIE (OFF PANEL): OH JEEZ.

SOPHIE (OFF PANEL): STACE, COME ON. THIS IS ALL MESSED UP.

SOPHIE (OFF PANEL): WE DON'T HAVE TO DO THIS.

STACIA: £$%& YOU.

SOPHIE: THIS IS STUPID.

SOPHIE: "SHE...SHE IS CLOSE BY; ABOVE; BENEATH; AFAR..."

SOPHIE: W-WE MUSTN'T DO THIS. THIS IS WRONG.

SOPHIE: YEAH, WELL, YOU'RE TOO LATE. IT'S DONE.

SOPHIE: "FIRE FROM THE SKY SHE BRINGS, PRO..."

SOHIE: BUT...

SOPHIE: BUT THIS IS BAD. THIS HAS NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE...

SOPHIE: H-HAS IT?

CAPTION: Thus the centuries were passed in wars of rat and snake, or in the dreams of glass-green beetles, coppered by the desert light.

CAPTION: In old Baghdad, Promethea split the clouds with Allah's fire, so that the rains were come, a hard and rattling mercy.

CAPTION: And in proud Constantinople did Promethea, in imitation of the Savior, drive out the money-lenders and false traders from the temple courtyards.

CAPTION: At last, tiring of the world, Promethea dwelled with Saints and Houris amongst sweet Paradise gardens of the Right and Only God.

CAPTION: Likewise, Promethea quit eventually this mortal realm for palaces of Heaven, with the One True Lord there to abide.

CAPTION: And they knew nothing of each other, both in differing Elysiums that did not conceive of a Dominion save their own.

CAPTION: And so the spirit of Promethea was divided in herself, and did not know it.

CAPTION: And the years were like grains pouring in the Present's hourglass throat, down into spent, still Past out of a crumbling and uncertain Future.

STACIA: HM.

STACIA: I DON'T THINK WE'VE BEEN INTRODUCED, HAVE WE, DARLING?

STACIA: WHAT HAVE YOU COME AS, EXACTLY?

SOPHIE: IT' STILL ME, BUT I'M DIFFERENT NOW. AND I'M RECLAIMING MY EARTHLY DUTIES.

SOPHIE: WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS, GRACE? THIS WASN'T OUR AGREEMENT.

STACIA: THINGS CHANGE, DARLING. FOR ALL OF US.

STACIA: I'VE GROWN RATHER ATTACHED TO PHYSICAL EXISTENCE.

STACIA: AND TO STACIA, AS I BELIEVE SHE MENTIONED.

SOPHIE: GRACE, THE GODDESS HAS APPOINTED ME PROMETHEA OF THIS ERA.

SOPHIE: COMPARED WITH THAT, YOU AND STACIA AREN'T IMPORTANT.

SOPHIE: I OUTRANK YOU NOW.

STACIA: ME? YOU OUTRANK ME?

STACIA: I AM GRACE £$%&ING BRANNAGH, DARLING, AND I'M THE BEST THERE'S EVER BEEN !

STACIA: I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS.

STACIA: DEFEND YOURSELF.

SOPHIE: GRACE, WE CAN WORK THIS OUT. DON'T...

ON BOOK: HISTORY

SOPHIE: -UHG...-

?: OH, JESUS...

?: OUT! EVERYBODY GET OUT!

STACIA: LITTLE BITCH...

STACIA: LITTLE SCHOOLGIRL THINKS SHE'S BETTER THAN ME...

SOPHIE (OFF PANEL): GRACE...

SOPHIE: I SAID DON'T.

STACIA: WH...*

STACIA: URRH...

SOPHIE: GRACE...STACIA... LOOK, I DIDN'T WANT TO DO THAT.

SOPHIE: BUT DON'T YOU SEE? EITHER WE STOP THIS NOW AND WORK THINGS OUT, OR IT'S WAR BETWEEN US.

STACIA: FAIR ENOUGH.

STACIA: THEN IT'S WAR.

SOPHIE: AAAAA!

CAPTION: And then, in the Eleventh Century, came the Crusades.

CAPTION: And from her sweet Islamic Paradise Promethea saw the conflict, and, descending unto Earth, did wage Jihad against the infidel.

CAPTION: And when news of the war was heard in Heaven, so Promethea came down and was a vengeful fire amongst the heathens.

CAPTION: And oft amid her dunes Promethea heard tell of another like her, yet that fought with the Crusaders, but believed it not.

CAPTION: While on the desert winds came stories to Promethea of one like she that sided with the Saracens, these tales she dismissed as fancies.

CAPTION: Thus, in the year 1097, they were met at Antioch.

JACK: UH-OH.

ON VEHICLE: J

ON VEHICLE: POLI-

ON SIGN: -E

ON WALL: L54

ON SIGN: PARK

ON SIGN: -Z  -A

KAREN: LUCE, IT'S HER. THE ONE WITH COLORED HAIR, AND... AND A NEW ONE.

LUCILLE: JESUS.

LUCILLE: COME ON. WE HAVE TO GET OVER THERE RIGHT NOW.

ON SIGN: Sa-

NEWSREADER (ON TV): ...DIFFERENT SCIENCE-HEROINES, BOTH CLAIMING TO BE PROMETHEA.

NEWSREADER (ON TV): MORE THAN TWO DOZEN PEOPLE HAVE BEEN INJURED, AND PROPERTY DAMAGE COULD RUN TO MILLIONS...

TRISH: SOPHIE...?

ON SIGN: -GB's

IN BACKGROUND: 17

MARGARET: DEAR GOD. THEY'RE FIGHTING. THIS IS UNPRECEDENTED.

BILL: I-- I DUNNO, MARGARET, HONEY. I'M GETTING REAL DEJA-VU HERE...

ANNA: MISTRESS BILL SPEAKS TRULY.

ANNA: THIS HAPPENED BEFORE.

CAPTION: Their war was terrible, yet not so fierce as the alarm that fluttered sudden in their souls, the dread that tolled now in their hearts.

CAPTION: Yet they fought on, and told themselves the tears that welled up unaccountably in both their eyes were caused by dust, by desert wind.

CAPTION: by smoke.

CAPTION: And within each of them, the spirit-child Promethea, divided in itself, began to weep and grow afraid, and yet did not know why.

CAPTION: And still they battled on, and knew each other not.

CAPTION: Screaming, cursing, each by different gods, they fought, each certain they alone were she, Promethea, the very principle of mankind's spiritual imaginings.

CAPTION: Like dogs they raged, they snarled.

CAPTION: Like dogs.

CAPTION: And the planes hit the buildings.

CAPTION: And the smartbomb hits the mosque.

CAPTION: The tanks roll over a demolished settlement.

CAPTION: The pretty student in the shopping precinct gets exactly halfway through her last defiant prayer.

CAPTION: So broadsword clashed against plumed spear.

CAPTION: Scimitar rang on blood-crossed shield.

CAPTION: And everything proceeded as it must.

CAPTION: At last, locked in their death-grip, two religions looked into each other's eyes and recognized themselves.

CAPTION: Knew then that both were halves of what had been one holy, undivided source.

CAPTION: Thus, drowning in their blood with realization mirrored in stunned eyes, they tried to kiss, but died before they did.

CAPTION: And the Promethea spirit, reunited with herself, held in her scream of horror, wiped the schism from her mind, forgot it quite...

CAPTION: ...until a great while later.

SOPHIE: I...

SOPHIE: OH GOD.

SOPHIE: W-WE...

ON SIGN: O-

ON SIGN: AG-

ON ROOF: 13

ON SIGN: -S

ON POSTER: THE LIMP  IN CONCERT

LUCILLE OR KAREN: AAAUUGH!

ON OBJECT: Chick

ON SIGN: S-

LUCILLE: JESUS CHRIST.

LUCILLE: JESUS CHRIST, WHAT THE £$%& WAS THAT?

KAREN: LUCILLE... LUCILLE, I'M HURT. MY ARM...

LUCILLE: IT'S OKAY, KAREN. I GOT YOU.

LUCILLE: HEY, YOU!WHAT HAPPENED?

?: I--I DUNNO. PEOPLE WERE FIGHTING, BUT... AW, £$%&.

?: £$%&, MY EARS ARE BLEEDING...

LUCILLE: OKAY, JUST STAY BACK. WE'RE FBI AGENTS, AND...

LUCILLE: HOLY @#~*. KAREN, IT'S THEM. COLORED-HAIR AND THE NEW ONE!

KAREN: L-LUCILLE, I'M GONNA PASS OUT...

LUCILLE: NO! KAREN, YOU STAY WITH ME, DAMN IT.

LUCILLE: THEY'RE OUT COLD. WE CAN TAKE THEM...

KAREN: NO. LUCILLE, LOOK.

KAREN: SOMETHING'S HAPPENING.

ON RUBBLE: -A-

LUCILLE: WHAT DO YOU...?

LUCILLE: OH @#~*.

ON SIGN: CLOVER'S

ON SIGN: R-

ON GROUND: S

BILL: MARGARET, SWEETHEART, WE SHOULDN'T OPEN A DOORWAY LIKE THIS. ONLY DEMONS DO THAT STUFF.

MARGARET: BILL, THIS IS AN EMERGENCY. WE'VE GOT TO LIMIT THE DAMAGE THAT'S ALREADY BEEN DONE.

MARGARET: ALL RIGHT, ANNA. WE'VE GOT THEM. YOU CAN SEAL UP THE APERTURE.

LUCILLE: KAREN, IT'S ALL OF THEM! SUBJECT 1901-1920, SUBJECT 1941-1970...

LUCILLE: KAREN?

KAREN: *

LUCILLE: NOW WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT ABOUT?

CAPTION: NEXT: A HIGHER COURT!