The Alan Moore Transcription Project presents:

VALLEY OF THE DOLLS

(comic strip from Promethea #29, May 2004)

(C) 2004 America's Best Comics, LLC

(transcription made from the original comic)

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

TRISH: SOPHIE?

TRISH: SOPHIE, WHAT'S GOING ON?

PROMETHEA: MOM, IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY. YOU PUT THE WAND INTO THE GRAIL...

TRISH: OH GOD. SOPHIE, I'M REAL. MY LIFE IS REAL. IT'S REALLY HAPPENING TO ME. THIS...

TRISH: ...THIS IS NOW.

DENNIS: IT'S GETTING BIGGER! WE HAVE TO GET AWAY...

PROMETHEA: DON'T BE SCARED, MOM. THIS IS JUST HOW IT HAPPENS.

JACK FAUST: NO, BUDDY. E-EVERYTHING'S GONNA BE FINE. I'M RIGHT HERE, DENNIS, OKAY?

TRISH: SOPHIE, A-AM I...OH GOD. AM I THE VIRGIN MARY OR SOMETHING?

STACIA: OH @#$*, LOOK AT ME! I'M A GONK. HOW DID I GET LIKE THIS?

PROMETHEA: NO. NO, YOU'RE NOT THE MADONNA. BUT THIS THING, THIS FEELING INSIDE YOU... THAT'S THE MADONNA.

PROMETHEA: SHE'S ALWAYS BEEN THERE, IN US ALL, BUT NOW SHE'S REVEALED...

PROMETHEA: NOW EVERYTHING IS REVEALED.

DOLL: HOW EXTRAORDINARY.

HEADING: P R O M E T H E A

HEADING: VALLEY OF THE DOLLS

DOLL: UM...

DOLL: LOOK, AT THE RISK OF APPEARING TERRIBLY NAIVE AND EVERYTHING...

DOLL: ...BUT WAS I THE ONLY ONE WHO THOUGHT I WAS THE ONLY ONE?

DOLL: I'M SO RELIEVED TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT! I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST ME.

DOLL: I'D REGAIN CONSCIOUSNESS IN THE RIVER...

DOLL: NO. NOT REGAIN...

DOLL: WE'VE PROBABLY ALL JUST WOKEN FOR THE FIRST TIME, EXCEPT WE HAVE THESE VAGUE MEMORIES...

DOLL: ...OF BEING HURT IN EXPLOSIONS! HE'S RIGHT!

DOLL: Y'KNOW, IF I'D SURFACED ALONE, I'D ASSUME I'D HAD A NARROW ESCAPE, AND THAT MY MEMORY WAS FOGGY FROM THE BLAST.

DOLL: SO WOULD I.

DOLL: WE'RE MACHINES, THEN? ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCES?

DOLL: APPARENTLY. FOLLOWING SOME SIMPLE PROGRAM, KILLING BASED ON UTILITY AND NOVELTY, SOMETHING LIKE THAT.

DOLL: SO THAT WOULD MEAN...

DOLL: ...OH.

DOLL: AH. YES, I SEE.

DOLL: OH DEAR.

CREDITS: ALAN MOORE WRITER  J.H. WILLIAMS III PENCILS, INKS, DIGITAL IMAGES  MICK GRAY INKS  JEROMY COX COLORS  TODD KLEIN LETTERS  KRISTY QUINN ASST. EDITOR  SCOTT DUNBIER EDITOR  MOORE & WILLIAMS III CREATORS

ROGER: MARV, THAT SOUNDS LIKE A LOT OF GUNFIRE FROM DOWN RIVER...

STAN: THAT'LL BE THE DOLLS ALL WAKING UP. PROBABLY THEY'RE MOWING DOWN EVENING STROLLERS.

MARV: STAN, YOU PSYCHOPATHIC BASTARD! HOW COULD YOU UNLEASH ALL THIS?

STAN: MARV, IT'S REALLY SIMPLE: I HATE YOU. I HATE ALL YOU GUYS, BUT EXPECIALLY YOU.

STAN: I MEAN, BOB HAD ALL THE MONEY SO HE WAS THE LEADER, UNTIL THAT STOCK MEETING AT THE WTC ON 9-11.

STAN: BUT THAT'S FAIR ENOUGH.

STAN: ROGER'S GOT SCIENCE-STRENGTH, SO SHE'S OUR MUSCLE. KENNETH'S OUR TELEPATH. THIS IS ALL FINE WITH ME.

STAN: BUT YOU! YOU'RE OUR GENIUS? HOW COME? WHAT DID YOU DO?

STAN: I MADE THE RAY-GUNS, THE HOVER-PLATFORM, THE SATELLITE...

STAN: I MADE THE DOLLS, MARV!

MARV: SO THAT'S WHY THE DOLL ONLY TRIED TO KILL ME...AND WHY SMILIAC HAD TO DIE BEFORE HE UNWITTINGLY GAVE YOUR MULTIPLE-BODY GAME AWAY.

ON TIE: 4

KENNETH: MARV, WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO? THAT GUNFIRE FROM DOWN RIVER...

KENNETH: ...IT SOUNDS LIKE THE WHOLE CITY'S GOING TO HELL.

?: IS THAT FIREWORKS? OR IS IT GUNS OR SOMETHING?

?: I-IS THERE A WAR GOING ON OUT THERE?

JACK FAUST: MAYBE.

JACK FAUST: MAYBE IT'S ALL THE WARS MANKIND EVER HAD, AND THEY'RE ALL ALWAYS HAPPENING RIGHT NOW.

JACK FAUST: MAYBE IT'S ALWAYS THE END OF THE WORLD.

DENNIS: I CAN'T STAND THIS! I CAN'T STAND WHAT'S INSIDE MY HEAD!

JACK FAUST: DENNIS, YOU DON'T HAVE A CHOICE. THERE'S NOWHERE TO ESCAPE TO.

JACK FAUST: WHAT'S INSIDE OUR HEADS AND WHAT'S OUTSIDE...I THINK THAT'S THE SAME PLACE NOW.

JACK FAUST: PERHAPS IT ALWAYS WAS.

TRISH: SOPHIE... E-EVERYTHING LOOKS DIFFERENT...

PROMETHEA: YES. SPACE AND TIME, OUR SELVES, OUR WHOLE WORLD... THESE THINGS ONLY EVER EXISTED IN OUR PERCEPTIONS.

PROMETHEA: NOW THOSE PERCEPTIONS ARE CHANGING.

TRISH: B-BUT, I MEAN, THIS WHOLE PLACE. IT'S LIKE IT IS IN MY DREAMS...

TRISH: IT'S LIKE THE ROOM, THE WHOLE BUILDING, IT'S SORT OF INFINITELY BIG, AND THERE'S DOORS WHERE THERE AREN'T ANY AND STUFF...

STACIA: YEAH, AND...AND SOMEHOW I ALWAYS LEAVE THE PEOPLE I'M WITH, JUST FOR A MINUTE, AND I NEVER FIND THEM AGAIN.

STACIA: AND...AND YOU KIND OF GET LOST...

JACK FAUST: YEAH. I HAVE DREAMS LIKE THAT. THE BIG HOUSE WITH THE WEIRD CLUTTERED STAIRS AND HALLWAYS, AND YOU'RE ALWAYS CLIMBING OR SOMETHING.

DENNIS: I HAD THAT. I HAD THAT EXACT SAME DREAM, ABOUT THE HOUSE.

DENNIS: A-AND SOME OF THE ROOMS ARE LIKE YOUR PARENTS' HOUSE, OR THE SCHOOL YOU WENT TO...

STACIA: YEAH. THE HOUSE... IT'S OUR LIFE, ISN'T IT?

?: IT'S LIKE OUR WHOLE LIFE HAPPENING AT ONCE, WITH ALL THE DIFFERENT ROOMS STUCK TOGETHER.

?: OUR LIFE. AND ALL THIS TIME, THIS IS WHERE WE'VE BEEN. IN THAT HOUSE...

JACK FAUST: Y'KNOW, SHE WAS RIGHT. EVERYBODY'S GETTING LOST.

PROMETHEA: YES. I THINK THAT'S MEANT TO HAPPEN.

PROMETHEA: JACK, THIS FEELS LIKE THE IMMATERIA...

JACK FAUST: YEAH. IT'S GETTING CLOSER, THE MOMENT WHEN EVERYBODY'S CONSCIOUSNESS SHIFTS FROM THE EARTHLY PLANE TO THE HIGHER SPHERES ABOVE.

JACK FAUST: WE'RE NEARLY THERE.

JACK FAUST: THE BIG THIRTY-TWO. THE GRAND FINALE. THE MATERIAL WORLD'S END.

JACK FAUST: THE OPENING OF THE THIRTY-SECOND PATH IS ALMOST HERE, SOPHIE...AND WE'RE ALL COMING ALONG ON THIS ONE.

JACK FAUST: EVERY SINGLE ONE OF US.

KAREN: DON'T LET GO!

KAREN: DON'T LET GO OF ME!

?: KAREN, SWEETHEART, WE'RE ALL RIGHT HERE...

?: MOMMY...

KAREN: DON'T LET GO! IF YOU LET GO, I'LL SLIP BACK DOWN INTO...

KAREN: OH GOD. OH GOD, DON'T LET ME END UP ON THAT ROOF.

HANSARD: I THINK THAT WE'VE DONE ALL THAT WE CAN FOR YOUR PARTNER, AGENT BALL.

HANSARD: I MEAN, WE GOT HER TO A HOSPITAL AND SHE'S WITH HER FAMILY.

HANSARD: WE NEED TO CONTACT WASHINGTON, GET A HANDLE ON WHAT IS HAPPENING HERE.

LUCILLE: YEAH. YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.

LUCILLE: JESUS. I--I NEVER SAW ANYBODY AS TERRIFIED AS KAREN IS BEFORE.

HANSARD: NO? WELL, THE NURSE I SPOKE TO SAID CASES LIKE AGENT BREUGHEL WERE POURING IN TONIGHT.

LUCILLE: YEAH, OKAY.

LUCILLE: GOD, WHAT IS THIS? IT'S NOT GAS, IT'S NOT A DISEASE...

HANSARD: LISTEN, I HAVE A SECURE LINE TO WASHINGTON SET UP IN RECEPTION...

HANSARD: I DON'T KNOW. IF IT'S SEIZURES CAUSED BY AN ELECTROMAGNETIC FIELD, THEN AT LEAST IT'S SOMETHING OUTSIDE US DOING THIS.

HANSARD: BECAUSE IF IT'S COMING FROM INSIDE US, THAT WOULD MEAN...

? (OFF PANEL): AGENT HANSARD? AGENT BALL? WE HAVE THE DIRECTOR GENERAL ON THE LINE.

ON BUILDING: E

LUCILLE: OKAY, I GOT IT.

LUCILLE: SIR, THIS IS AGENT BALL. SIR, WE'VE GOT A SITUATION HERE.

LUCILLE: THE PROMETHEA CASE... SHE RETURNED TO NEW YORK AND FREED HER ASSOCIATES, AND NOW EVERYTHING'S GONE CRAZY. MY PARTNER...

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): WE KNOW ABOUT AGENT BREUGHEL. WHERE'S THE TARGET CURRENTLY LOCATED?

LUCILLE: PROMETHEA? W-WE DON'T KNOW, SIR . SHE'S SOMEWHERE IN THE CITY...

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): FIND HER. FIND HER AND TERMINATE HER, BEFORE THIS SPREADS.

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): THERE'S ALREADY CRACKS SHOWING IN WASHINGTON, BETWEEN RICE, RUMSFELD, THE SECURITY SERVICES, THE WHITE HOUSE...

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): FINISH THIS BEFORE SOMEBODY ORDERS SOMETHING STUPID.

HANSARD: UH...WHAT DO YOU MEAN, SIR? WHAT...

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): HANSARD, SOME SORT OF REALITY-CANCER SITUATED IN MANHATTAN IS THREATENING THE ENTIRE WORLD. WORK IT OUT FOR YOURSELVES.

DIRECTOR GENERAL (ON LAPTOP): GOD BE WITH YOU, AGENTS. OVER AND OUT.

LUCILLE: B-BUT... WHAT HE JUST SAID. DID HE MEAN...?

HANSARD: I--I DON'T KNOW. IT SOUNDED LIKE... NO. THEY WOULDN'T DO THAT.

HANSARD: L-LOOK, WE JUST HAVE TO FIND HER. GET IMAGING EQUIPMENT, PINPOINT HER LOCATION, THEN ALL THIS GOES AWAY, AND...

HANSARD: HEY. HEY, THAT'S STRANGE. THAT GUNFIRE WE HEARD EARLIER...

HANSARD: ...IT'S STOPPED.

HANSARD: I WONDER WHY?

DOLL: CURSES.

DOLL: DITTO.

DOLL: YOU KNOW, IF I MAY VENTURE A REMARK, AFTER KILLING NEARLY FIFTY OF MYSELF, KILLING YOU DOESN'T SEEM VERY NOVEL.

DOLL: AGREED. OR VERY PRACTICAL.

DOLL: SHALL WE, THEN? ON THREE? ONE... TWO...

DOLL: THERE. THAT'S MUCH BETTER. NOW WE CAN POOL OUR RESOURCES AND REALLY ACCOMPLISH THINGS!

DOLL: ABSOLUTELY! I MEAN, WE MUST HAVE A CREATOR SOMEWHERE, HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT THAT? IF WE'VE...

DOLL: WHOOPS! STEADY AS SHE GOES...

DOLL: ANYWAY, AS I WAS SAYING, IF WE'VE ALL BEEN ACTIVATED AT ONCE, SOMETHING'S OBVIOUSLY WRONG.

?: HEY! HEY, LOOK OVER THERE! IT'S HIM!

DOLL: PERHAPS OUR CREATOR'S IN TROUBLE? MAYBE WE SHOULD...

?: IT'S THE ANGEL OF DEATH!

DOLL: WHAT ON EARTH...?

?: WE'RE HUGE FANS, LOVELY ONE, AND NOW THE WORLD'S ENDING!

DOLL: A-ARE YOU MAD? I'M THE PAINTED DOLL! STAY BACK, OR...

?: YES! GRANT US A QUICK DEATH, BEFORE DEMONS AND THINGS TURN UP!

SFX: BLADDAMM BLADDAMM

?: -UKKH- ...TH-THANK YOU...

?: ME NEXT! ME NEXT!

DOLL: GOOD GRIEF! THEY'RE ALL OVER ME!

DOLL: RUN! SAVE YOURSELF! FIND OUR CREATOR AND DO WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE!

?: GHA...*

SFX: BLADDAM

?: HEY! HEY, I WAS BEFORE YOU!

SFX: BLADDAMM

SFX: BLADDA-  BLADDAM

DENNIS: Y'KNOW, THEY...THEY DID THIS COMIC BOOK ABOUT ME ONCE? ONLY THEY CALLED ME DIRK, NOT DENNIS.

DENNIS: AND WHAT I KEEP THINKING IS, AM I THE GUY THAT'S REAL, OR IS IT THE GUY IN THE COMIC BOOK?

STACIA: I--I NEED THE BATHROOM...

DENNIS: YEAH. YEAH, I THINK I DO, TOO. I--I CAN'T REALLY TELL RIGHT NOW.

DENNIS: BOY. BOY, THIS IS A LONG HALLWAY.

STACIA: IT WASN'T HERE BEFORE.

STACIA: O-OR WAS IT? IS THIS HOW IT ALWAYS WAS, WITH ALL THESE DOORS, AND...

STACIA: GRACE...?

STACIA: OH GOD. OH, LOVER, I NEVER WANTED YOU TO SEE ME LIKE THIS. I'M ALL FAT AND I'M ALL STUPID...

GRACE: HUSH, SWEETHEART. YOU'RE UTTERLY PERFECT... AND I'VE COME TO BE WITH YOU FOR THE END.

GRACE: EVERYONE'S COMING THROUGH, DARLING. ABSOLUTELY EVERYONE.

CAPTION: THe LOVErs

STACIA: OH, GRACE. GRACE, I LOVE YOU SO MUCH...

GRACE: I KNOW. I KNOW YOU DO.

GRACE: DON'T LOOK SO UNHAPPY, MR. DRUCKER, DARLING.

GRACE: YOURS IS WAITING NEXT DOOR.

DENNIS: OH NO. OH, JESUS, I'M SORRY. I'M SO SORRY...

DENNIS: -AHUH- -AHUHUH-HUH...-

BILL (OFF PANEL): DENNIS, HONEY, IT'S ALL RIGHT. EVERYTHING'S ALL RIGHT NOW.

BILL: NOW WE CAN BE TOGETHER.

BILL: NOW EVERYONE CAN BE TOGETHER.

IN SEALS: ·1625·  ·SIGILLUM·CIVITATIS·NOVI·EBORACI·

UVULA: Y'KNOW, THIS CITY IS GOING STRAIGHT TO ANAL.

UVULA: IN A HANDCART.

GARY: B-BUT MS. MAYOR...UVULA, LISTEN, SHOULDN'T YOU BE CONSULTING WITH WASHINGTON ABOUT EMERGENCY PROCEDURES, OR...

UVULA: SUGAR, PLEASE! IT'S LIKE MY CHARACTER SAID IN JAWGASM IV...

UVULA: "OHH! OH GOD, BABY, LOOK AT THAT! IT'S ALL OVER!"

GARY: MS. CASCADE, PLEASE, THE PEOPLE NEED REASSURING...

UVULA: NO THEY DON'T. IT'S TOO LATE FOR THAT STUFF.

UVULA: THEY NEED TO THINK ABOUT THE FOURWAY WITH THE NEIGHBORS THEY'VE NEVER DARED SUGGEST.

UVULA: LATER, YOU GUYS. HUGS.

GARY: DAMN.

GARY: HELL, PHIL. YOU THINK SHE'S RIGHT?

PHIL: YEAH. YEAH, GARY, I DO. LOOK, DO YOU...

PHIL: ...D-DO YOU WANT TO FOOL AROUND, OR ANYTHING?

UVULA: HEY. HEY, I KNOW YOU! YOU'RE THAT NUTS GUY WHO WAS MAYOR BEFORE ME!

UVULA: GOD, THIS IS SO WEIRD...

SONNY: BEDAD, AND YOU'RE A FINE STRAPPING COLLEEN, NOW.

SONNY: A-are you my new mommy?

UVULA: SONNY, RIGHT? SONNY BASKERVILLE? I'M UVULA CASCADE. I GOT YOUR JOB.

UVULA: GOD, IT'S PERFECT, MEETING YOU HERE...

SONNY: Oh, sister! How I've wanted for another woman's company.

SONNY: SHADDUP, BITCH! LET A REAL MAN TALK TO THE LADY!

UVULA: WOW. THIS WHOLE MULTIPHASIC THING IS SUCH A TURN-ON!

UVULA: DO YOU GUYS WANT TO PARTY? I MEAN, IT'S THE APOCALYPSE AND EVERYTHING.

SONNY: HEY, BEND OVER, BABY. I'LL DRIVE.

SONNY: L-Little Sonny's FWIGHTENED! Th-There's SCARY people!

UVULA: SCARY PEOPLE? WHAT DO YOU M...

UVULA: OH.

DAISY: TIME TO WAKE UP, MR. BRANNIGAN! RISE AND SLIME !

SPLASH: WUZZUNK?

SPLASH: HEY, I WAS JUST RESTING MY EYES! I'M THE SQUIRT WHO'S ALERT! I'M THE SEEP THAT DOESN'T SLEEP!

SPLASH: WHERE AM I?

TOM: HELLO, SPLASH. YOU'RE IN NEW YORK.

ON BODY: S

TOM: PROMETHEA'S ENDING THE WORLD, SO I'VE REASSEMBLED AMERICA'S BEST.

SPLASH: TOM STRONG! WHY, YOU OLD GRAVITY-WARPED GALOOT!

SPLASH: I'M VICIOUS, I'M VISCOUS, AND I HAVE A MENISCUS! PUT IT THERE!

TOM: UH ... ACTUALLY, THIS OUTFIT IS JUST CLEAN.

GREYSHIRT: TOM? WE'RE GETTING SOMETHING ON MISS RAY'S SCANNER...

JONNI: FRANK'S RIGHT, MR. STRONG. THIS REALITY WARP RADIATES FROM A POINT ABOUT FIVE BLOCKS SOUTH. THAT MUST BE WHERE PROMETHEA IS.

COBWEB: WHAT IS THAT BOY DOING?

COBWEB: AND WHERE DID HE GET ALL THIS GHASTLY MACHINERY?

JACK B. QUICK: IT'S MOSTLY KITCHEN UTENSILS AND SIMPLE HOUSEHOLD INGREDIENTS, BY CRACKY!

JACK B. QUICK: OH, AND SOME NUCLEAR BOMBS AND SMALLPOX. I CALL IT MY "DOOMSDAY DEVICE."

COBWEB: B-BUT... WEREN'T WE SUPPOSED TO BE PREVENTING DOOMSDAY, YOU ADORABLE LITTLE DICKENS?

JACK B. QUICK: EXACTLY, YOU POOR UNSCIENTIFIC FOOLS!

JACK B. QUICK: THAT IS WHY I SHALL WAIT UNTIL MY DOOMSDAY DEVICE HAS REACHED CRITICAL MASS...

JACK B. QUICK: ...AND THEN USE A BIG RED-PAINTED HANDLE TO THROW IT INTO REVERSE!

JACK B. QUICK: NOW, ARE THERE ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?

JACK FAUST: HEY.

JACK FAUST: HEY, WHERE'D DENNIS GO? AND STACIA? I WAS WATCHING OUT FOR THEM...

PROMETHEA: I THINK WE ALL HAVE TO BE ALONE FOR THIS. I THINK THE END OF THE WORLD IS PERSONAL.

TRISH: OH, GOD! WHAT ABOUT MY NEIGHBORS? WHAT'S HAPPENING TO THEM?

JACK FAUST: I--I DUNNO. I THOUGHT I COULD HEAR SOMEBODY WEEPING, THEN I THOUGHT MAYBE THEY WERE LAUGHING...

TRISH: BUT THIS LIGHT. IT FILLS THE ROOM NOW. IS IT STILL EXPANDING, INTO THE OTHER APARTMENTS?

TRISH: TH-THE BROWNS DOWNSTAIRS HAVE A KID. A-AND MRS. O'SHEA'S OLD...

TRISH: I MEAN, IS THIS...IS THIS STUFF HAPPENING TO EVERYBODY? E-EVEN PEOPLE IN OTHER STATES? OTHER COUNTRIES?

JACK FAUST: YEAH...OR IT WILL BE SOON. I'M NOT EVEN SURE "SOON" MEANS ANYTHING NOW.

JACK FAUST: THIS HAPPENS TO EVERYBODY. THIS IS HOW THE WORLD ENDS.

CAPTION: the ChariOt

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): AND I'M A MAGICIAN. I'M SUPPOSED TO BE PREPARED FOR THIS, AND BETWEEN YOU AND ME, LADY, I'M NOT.

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): BETWEEN YOU AND ME, I'M TERRIFIED.

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): SET ALONE KNOWS HOW EVERYBODY ELSE MUST BE FEELING.

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): SOME WILL TRY TO HIDE FROM IT. SOME WILL WELCOME IT.

ON BOTTLE: SHAVA Shampoo

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): SOME WILL RECOGNIZE IT FROM SOMEWHERE...

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): ...WILL HAVE SOMEHOW KNOWN ALL THEIR LIVES THAT THE END WOULD BE LIKE THIS.

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): EXACTLY...

JACK FAUST (OFF PANEL): EXACTLY LIKE THIS.

DOLL: WELL, NOW.

DOLL: DO YOU KNOW, THIS IS THE VERY LAST THING I WAS EXPECTING.

ON SIGN: -OS ANGEL-

DOLL: MY INTUITION... AND I SUPPOSE THAT'S JUST A PROGRAM, ISN'T IT?

DOLL: MY INTUITION TELLS ME ONE OF YOU CLOWNS MUST BE MY CREATOR.

MARV: OH, #~@*. QUICKLY, SOMEBODY!

MARV: TAKE HIM OUT BEFORE...

MARV: ...HE...

ROGER: AARNH!

DOLL: THERE. ALL SETTLED.

DOLL: YOU KNOW, IT WOULD SAVE ME ABSOLUTELY TONS OF TIME IF SOMEBODY WOULD JUST SAY WHICH OF YOU CREATED ME.

STAN: YEAH, THAT'D BE ME. I GAVE YOU LIFE. NOW MAYBE YOU COULD OFF THESE OTHER LOSERS FOR ME?

ROGER: URRNGH... S-STAN, YOU SON OF A BITCH...

STAN: AND MAKE SURE YOU KILL MARV FIRST! HE'S THE ONE I HATE WORST!

DOLL: OH, DADDY... CAN I CALL YOU DADDY? DADDY, HOW I'VE WAITED FOR THIS MOMENT!

DOLL: BUT TELL ME, WHY DID YOU WAKE ALL US LITTLE SCAMPS UP NOW?

STAN: UH...BECAUSE IT LOOKS LIKE GOD'S ENDING THE WORLD.

STAN: EVERYTHING'S GETTING REVEALED, AND THESE GUYS GUESSED MY SECRET.

STAN: ANYWAY, AFTER MARV, SHOOT ROGER! THAT'S NO-NUTS OVER THERE...

DOLL: OH, DADDY, YOU'RE SO PERFECT! YOU'RE MY CREATOR AND YOU CONTROL MY DESTINY. THAT'S NOVEL AND PRACTICAL!

STAN: WHAT?

SFX: PcHuTT

DOLL: OH, COME ON! WHAT WAS I GOING TO DO?

DOLL: ANYWAY, HE WAS NEVER THERE FOR ME WHEN I NEEDED ADVICE ABOUT GIRLS AND BASEBALL.

DOLL: AND INCIDENTALLY, WHY DIDN'T SOMEBODY TELL ME THIS WAS THE APOCALYPSE?

DOLL: I WAS ONLY BORN EARLIER THIS EVENING. I'D ASSUMED THINGS WERE ALWAYS LIKE THIS.

DOLL: INSTEAD I FIND OUT AT THE LAST MINUTE THAT GOD (NOVEL) IS PLANNING TO END THE WORLD (PRACTICAL)!

DOLL: EVIDENTLY, I HAVE WORK TO DO.

DOLL: I MUST DASH...

DOLL: ...I MUST DANCE...

DOLL: I MUST FOLLOW MY HEART!

DOLL: I WAS ALWAYS THE LIVELIEST WIRE IN THE TOASTER.

DOLL: I ALWAYS KNEW BEST.

DOLL: OH, THEY SAID GOD WAS DEAD, ALL THOSE BEATNIKS AND SNOOTY-ASS FRENCHMEN.

DOLL: NOT ME. I KNEW BETTER.

DOLL: I SAID TO THEM, "WAIT, BOYS!"

DOLL: "DON'T BREAK COVER YET AWHILE."

DOLL: "HE MIGHT BE FAKING."

DOLL: "I MEAN, THEY THOUGHT SADDAM WAS DEAD."

DOLL (OFF PANEL): "AND THE NOVEL."

DOLL (OFF PANEL): "AND GLENN CLOSE IN THAT LAST SCENE OF FATAL ATTRACTION."

DOLL: THAT'S WHAT I SAID. BUT DID THEY LISTEN? OHH NO. THEY WENT RIGHT AHEAD AND ORGANIZED GOD'S FUNERAL.

DOLL: WELL, DON'T COUNT YOUR CHICKENS...

DOLL: ...BEFORE THEY COME HOME TO ROOST...

DOLL: ...THAT'S WHAT I ALWAYS SAY...

DOLL: ...AND IF YOU WANT A JOB DONE PROPERLY...

DOLL: ...DO IT YOURSELF.

ON PAPER: FANTASTIC BARGAINS

ON PAPER: CLOSING DOWN

ON PAPER: NEXT: EVERYTHING MUST GO!