The Alan Moore Transcription Project presents:

WRAPPARTY

(comic strip from Promethea #32, April 2005)

(C) 2005 America's Best Comics, LLC

(transcription made from the original comic)

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

PROMETHEA: WELL, MY LOVES, WE'RE AT THE END. AT THE DEATH, IF YOU LIKE...ALTHOUGH LIKE DEATH, THERE'S PLENTY MORE SURPRISES ON THE OTHER SIDE.

PROMETHEA: BUT WHILE WE'RE HERE AND ALIVE, LET'S BE GLAD.

CAPTION: 16 TAROT PATH: THE HEIROPHANT. ZODIAC SIGN: TAURUS. COLOR: DEEP INDIGO. JEWEL: TOPAZ. PLANT: MALLOW. PERFUME: STORAX. ANIMAL: BULL.

PROMETHEA: LET'S CELEBRATE.

CAPTION: Einstein's Spacetime is a timeless four-dimensional solid, containing every instant simultaneously, forever...including our lives. DEATH, therefore, is a perspective illusion of the third dimension. Don't worry.

HEADING: WRAPPARty

CAPTION: A funeral CELEBRATION, or WAKE, dominates James Joyce's FINNEGANS WAKE, in which all human experience is distilled into one timeless day. Cheers!

CREDITS: ALAN MOORE WRITER J.H.WILLIAMS III ARTIST-DESIGNER TODD KLEIN LETTERER - DESIGNER SCOTT DUNBIER EDITOR KRISTY QUINN ASST. EDITOR

CAPTION: 29 TAROT PATH: THE MOON. ZODIAC SIGN: PISCES. COLOR: BUFF FLECKED WITH SILVER. JEWEL: PEARL. PLANT: OPIUM POPPY. PERFUME: AMBERGRIS. ANIMAL: DOLPHIN, FISH.

PROMETHEA: AFTER ALL, WE'VE PLENTY WORTH CELEBRATING DESPITE ALL THE WORLD'S CARNAGE.

PROMETHEA: THE SILVER OF OUR IMAGINATION. THE SOUL'S GOLD...

PROMETHEA: ...THE WONDER OF OUR PERCEPTIONS, ARRANGING THIS RANDOM SWIRL OF PARTICLES ABOUT US INTO A REALITY.

CAPTION: Modern science acknowledges, with the mystics, that there are other REALITIES beyond our conventional human construct.

CAPTION: Reality, essentially, is a field of INFORMATION, through which all of us perceiving entities roam as what physicist Murray Gell-Man called "Information Gathering and Utilizing Systems," or IGUSs. (Unless that means "It's God, Understanding Something.")

CAPTION: 17 TAROT PATH: THE LOVERS. ZODIAC SIGN: GEMINI. COLOR: PALE MAUVE. JEWEL: ALEXANDRITE, TOURMALINE, ICELAND SPAR. PLANT: ORCHID. PERFUME: WORMWOOD. ANIMAL: MAGPIE, ALL HYBRIDS.

PROMETHEA: HERE, ON THE OTHER SIDE...IF FICTION IS REALITY'S FLIPSIDE...LET'S CELEBRATE IMAGINATION.

PROMETHEA: LIKE PERCEPTION OF REALITY, IMAGINATION IS FLEXIBLE, CAN SUDDENLY INVERT ITSELF, CARTWHEELING GLORIOUSLY FROM ONE CONCEPT TO THE NEXT.

PROMETHEA: IMAGINATION CAN DO ANYTHING.

CAPTION: cerebrum

CAPTION: brain stem

CAPTION: cerebellum

CAPTION: Intelligence is not based upon the number of the brain's neurons, but how many CONNECTIONS we forge between them, linking one concept, one neuron with another, in a shimmering, self-aware neural net.

CAPTION: The number of potential neural connections in the human brain exceeds the number of particles in the known Universe.

CAPTION: 4 SEPHIRA: CHESED OR MERCY. PLANET: JUPITER. GODS: ZEUS, THOR, INDRA AND OTHER SKY GODS. DAY OF THE WEEK: THURSDAY. COLOR: BLUE. JEWEL: SAPPHIRE. PLANT: OLIVE, SHAMROCK. PERFUME: CEDAR. ANIMAL: UNICORN.

PROMETHEA: AN ANGEL SOMERSAULTING THROUGH OUR CONSCIOUSNESS, IMAGINATION DERIVES FROM IMAGE, A COLORFUL FORM UNFOLDING MENTALLY.

PROMETHEA: IMAGE HAS THE SAME ROOT WORD AS IMAGO, AN ADULT INSECT.

PROMETHEA: WHICH BRINGS ME TO THE MATTER OF MY NAME.

CAPTION: Both angels and imaginative thoughts, being phenomena not reliably repeatable under laboratory conditions, are equally outside the province of empirical science.

CAPTION: Consciousness, unprovable by scientific standards, is forever, then, the impossible phantom in the predictable biologic machine, and your every thought a genuine supernatural event. Your every thought is a ghost, dancing.

HEADING: PRoMETHEA

CAPTION: 1 SEPHIRA: KETHER OR THE CROWN. GODS: JEHOVA, ALLAH, OTHER MONOTHEISTIC DEITIES. COLOR: BRILLIANT WHITE. JEWEL: DIAMOND. PLANT: FLOWERING ALMOND. PERFUME: AMBERGRIS. ANIMAL: GOD.

PROMETHEA: "PROMETHEA."

PROMETHEA: AN IMAGINARY FICTIONAL CHARACTER WHO MANIFESTS IN REALITY THROUGH THE ARTISTS AND WRITERS THAT TELL HER STORY.

PROMETHEA: OBVIOUSLY, THE NAME'S A FEMININE VERSION OF PROMETHEUS, WHICH MEANS "FORETHOUGHT" ... WHICH MEANS "IMAGINATION."

PROMETHEA: SO THAT'S APPROPRIATE.

CAPTION: Promethea is also a title character in The Book of Promethea by Helene Cixous, where she is "a heroine of infinity" summoned from the writer's imagination. The current authors were unaware of this work when creating their comic-book incarnation.

CAPTION: Saturniidae Callosamia promethea is also the name of a species of moth.

CAPTION: 20 TAROT PATH: THE HERMIT. ZODIAC SIGN: VIRGO. COLOR: SLATE GRAY. JEWEL: PERIDOT. PLANT: LILY, SNOWDROP, NARCISSUS. PERFUME: NARCISSUS. ANIMAL: VIRGIN, ANCHORITE, ANY SOLITARY PERSON OR ANIMAL.

PROMETHEA: IMAGINATION...TUMBLING, SPINNING...IS THE LIGHT THAT GUIDES HUMANITY INTO ITS FUTURE.

PROMETHEA: THE HEAVEN-STOLEN LIGHT PROMETHEUS GAVE MANKIND. A BRIGHT, FORBIDDEN KNOWLEDGE, SNAKE-GRANTED IN EDEN.

PROMETHEA: THAT SERPENT'S NAME, LUCIFER, MEANS "LIGHT-BRINGER," INCIDENTALLY.

CAPTION: In Hebrew numerology, letters have number-values. The word for the Biblical serpent, nechesh, adds up to 358, as does messiach, meaning "messiah," another light-bringer.

CAPTION: Usually, the fire-and-light bringer, be it Prometheus, Loki or Jesus, is bound or nailed somewhere in punishment, often with their side ravaged or pierced.

PROMETHEA: THIS LIGHT, THIS PALACE OF IMAGINATION, IS MANKIND'S INHERITANCE, A BLAZING, LUNAR IMMATERIA THAT THE FINAL 32ND PATH REVEALS.

PROMETHEA: LET US BE ANGELS, BE MAGICIANS.

PROMETHEA: LET US MAKE OUR WORKS IN THESE BRIGHT FIELDS FOREVER.

CAPTION: JOHN KENDRICK BANGS 1862-1922

CAPTION: A fiction-populated twilight world was also proposed by author John Kendrick Bangs, (1862-1922).

CAPTION: The Immateria, consciousness imagined as space, populated by fictions, resembles mysticism's astral plane, composed of "astral light," pervading everything.

CAPTION: Consciousness Studies, fastest-growing science since 1994, sometimes describes consciousness as radiation, permeating our brains and the Universe.

CAPTION: 32 TAROT PATH: THE UNIVERSE. PLANET: SATURN. COLOR: BLACK. JEWEL: ONYX. PLANT: ASH, CYPRESS, HELLEBORE, YEW, NIGHTSHADE. PERFUME: ASAFOETIDA, SCAMMONY, INDIGO, SULPHUR, ALL "EVIL" ODORS. ANIMAL: CROCODILE.

PROMETHEA: CONSCIOUSNESS IS AN ASTOUNDING GIFT, TOO PRECIOUS TO BE SQUANDERED ON MATERIAL CONCERNS ALONE.

PROMETHEA: AND CONSCIOUSNESS, MODERN THEORY MAINTAINS, IS BUILT ON LANGUAGE.

PROMETHEA: BEFORE WE'RE CONSCIOUS OF SOMETHING, WE MUST HAVE A WORD FOR IT.

CAPTION: 13 TAROT PATH: THE HIGH PRIESTESS. PLANET: THE MOON. COLOR: SILVER. JEWEL: MOONSTONE, PEARL, CRYSTAL. PLANT: HAZEL, ALMOND, MUGWORT, MOONWORT, RANUNCULUS. PERFUME: MENSTRUAL BLOOD, CAMPHOR, ALOES, ALL SWEET "VIRGINAL" ODORS. ANIMAL: DOG.

CAPTION: The only reality we can ever truly know is that of our perceptions, our own consciousness, while that consciousness, and thus our entire reality, is made of nothing but signs and symbols. Nothing  but language.

CAPTION: Even God requires language before conceiving the Universe. See Genesis: "In the beginning was the Word."

PROMETHEA: REPRESENTING THINGS WITH SOUNDS OR MARKS, AS WITH ART AND LANGUAGE, WAS A HANDSPRING IN CONSCIOUSNESS ALLOWING US WONDERFUL NEW ABILITIES.

PROMETHEA: WE DIDN'T CALL IT ART, LANGUAGE OR CONSCIOUSNESS BACK THEN.

PROMETHEA: IT WAS ALL MAGIC.

CAPTION: 9 SEPHIRA: YESOD, OR FOUNDATION. PLANET: THE MOON. GODS: DIANA, SELENE, SHU, GANESA, HECATE, ALL LUNAR GODS AND GODDESSES. DAY OF THE WEEK: MONDAY. COLOR: VIOLET. JEWEL: QUARTZ. PLANT: BANYAN, MANDRAKE, DAMIANA. PERFUME: JASMINE, GINSENG, ALL ODORIFEROUS ROOTS. ANIMAL: ELEPHANT.

CAPTION: Consciousness, art, language and magic (known as "The Art") share a vocabulary: poetry uses invocation and evocation, as does sorcery. Casting spells is simply spelling, while the Black Book, or grimoire, is merely a Grammar.

CAPTION: Magician Aleister Crowley (1875 - 1947) famously described magic as "a disease of language."

CAPTION: 28 TAROT PATH: THE STAR. ZODIAC SIGN: AQUARIUS. COLOR: SKY BLUE. JEWEL: ARTICIAL GLASS. PLANT: OLIVE, COCONUT. PERFUME: GALBANUM. ANIMAL: MAN, EAGLE, PEACOCK.

PROMETHEA: MAGIC, A SCIENCE OF EVERYTHING, WAS HOW WE UNDERSTOOD THE UNIVERSE.

PROMETHEA: EXAMINING DETAILS, WE REDUCED EVERYTHING TO CATEGORIES. SCIENCE, ART, RELIGION, FRAGMENTING OUR WORLDVIEW.

PROMETHEA: GRADUALLY, HOWEVER, MANKIND'S RECONNECTING THINGS INTO ONE PERSPECTIVE. INTO MAGIC.

PROMETHEA: REJOICE!

CAPTION: One principle of Alchemy is that of "Solvé et Coagula," to dissolve and recombine. "Solvé" is reductionism, taking things apart for study (or "analysis"). "Coagula" is holism, reconnecting everything into a better and more accurate picture (or "synthesis").

CAPTION: Alchemy, then, rather than transmuting metals, is more concerned with transmuting humanity.

CAPTION: 24 TAROT PATH: DEATH. ZODIAC SIGN: SCORPIO. COLOR: DULL BROWN. JEWEL: SNAKESTONE. PLANT: CACTUS. PERFUME: SIAMESE BENZOIN, OPOPONAX. ANIMAL: SCORPION, BEETLE, LOBSTER OR CRAYFISH, WOLF.

PROMETHEA: MAGIC, AFTER ALL, IS RULED BY HERMES, HIS SYMBOL THIS CADUCEUS, ITS DOUBLE-HELIX SERPENTS REPRESENTING MANKIND'S EVOLUTION.

PROMETHEA: THEY WIND APART, THEN RECOMBINE, PROGRESSING UP TIME'S AXIS TOWARDS THEIR ULTIMATE SYNTHESIS.

PROMETHEA: TOWARDS WINGED, BLAZING GODHEAD.

CAPTION: According to Alchemy, before this fiery illumination, this gold, can occur, there is a period of uncertainty, darkness, putrefaction and despair. This is called the negredo.

CAPTION: Hermes Trismegistus, legendary founder of Alchemy, implies that the twin snakes represent our human microcosm and the celestial macrocosm in his axiom: "As above, so below."

PROMETHEA: PROMETHEA, THE PROMETHEA MOTH'S NAMESAKE, REPRESENTS HUMANITY'S EVOLVING SOUL; WHAT ANCIENT GREEKS FIRST NAMED OUR "PSYCHE."

PROMETHEA: ADDING "DELOS" (TO REVEAL), HUMPHREY OSMOND, A COLLEAGUE OF ALDOUS HUXLEY'S COINED "PSYCHEDELIC" OR "SOUL REVEALING."

PROMETHEA: MAGIC, THEREFORE, IS ALWAYS PSYCHEDELIC.

CAPTION: The Greek word psyche, to describe the human mind, soul or essence, was not a new word to the Greeks, but had previously been used to mean "butterfly" or "moth."

CAPTION: The butterfly's random fluttering from one point to another also accurately models how thought follows a fractal path from concept to concept.

CAPTION: 5 SEPHIRA: GEBURAH, OR STRENGTH. PLANET: MARS. GODS: ARES, MARS, TYR, VISHNU, HORUS, ALL MARTIAL GODS. DAY OF THE WEEK: TUESDAY. COLOR: RED. JEWEL: RUBY. PLANT: OAK, NUX VOMICA, NETTLE. PERFUME: TOBACCO. ANIMAL: BASILISK.

CAPTION: Theorist Julian Jaynes has suggested that even our own minds, voices inside our heads, would seem like supernatural visitations to people with no concept of consciousness.

PROMETHEA: OUR EARLIEST CAVE PAINTINGS SEEMED MAGICAL AND PSYCHEDELIC TO PEOPLE WITH NO CONCEPT OF DRAWN LINES REPRESENTING PEOPLE OR ANIMALS.

CAPTION: 8 SEPHIRA: HOD, OR SPLENDOUR. PLANET: MERCURY. GODS: HERMES, MERCURY, ODIN, THOTH, ALL MAGIC AND LANGUAGE GODS. DAY OF THE WEEK: WEDNESDAY. COLOR: ORANGE. JEWEL: OPAL. PLANT: MOLY (MANDRAKE), ANHALONIUM LEWINII. PERFUME: STORAX. ANIMAL: HERMAPHRODITE, JACKAL.

PROMETHEA: NAVIGATING DARK TUNNELS INTO TORCHLIT CAVERNS, OUR ANCESTORS PROBABLY PERCEIVED REAL FLYING ANTELOPES AND BISON.

CAPTION: Early audiences for Winsor McCay's Gertie the Dinosaur, in 1914, believed they were seeing a live prehistoric monster on stage, having no concept of cartoon animation.

PROMETHEA: IN THE PRIMITIVE ROCK PAINTINGS AND CREATION MYTHS OF SOUTH AMERICA, THE SNAKE SEEMS TO PREDOMINATE.

PROMETHEA: THIS CREATOR-SERPENT...OR OFTEN TWO SEPARATE SNAKES, LIKE THE CADUCEUS...IS CONTACTED USING THE PSYCHEDELIC PLANT EXTRACT AYAHUASCA.

CAPTION: 21 TAROT PATH: WHEEL OF FORTUNE. PLANET: JUPITER. COLOR: BLUE. JEWEL: AMETHYST, LAPIS LAZULI. PLANT: OAK, HYSSOP, FIG, POPLAR. PERFUME: SAFFRON, ALL 'GENEROUS' ODORS. ANIMAL: EAGLE.

CAPTION: In The Cosmic Serpent, ethnobotanist Jeremy Narby suggests twin snakes as an icon projected by our double-spiral DNA, as conscious entity.

CAPTION: Brains regularly replace all neurons, leaving nowhere to store memory. It's suggested that we over-write memories on our "junk" DNA, implying comunication from organism to DNA, contradicting standard theory.

PROMETHEA: THE SERPENTS ARE OFTEN ASSOCIATED WITH PLANT WISDOM. GREEK MEDICINE GOD AESCLEPIUS OBTAINED IT FROM SNAKES. RAINFOREST INDIANS RECEIVE IT IN SNAKE-GRANTED AYAHUASCA VISIONS.

PROMETHEA: IF SERPENTS REPRESENT DNA (ALSO IN PLANTS), THIS MAKES SENSE.

CAPTION: 25 TAROT PATH: TEMPERANCE OR ART. ZODIAC SIGN: SAGITTARIUS. COLOR: YELLOW. JEWEL: JACINTH. PLANT: RUSH. PERFUME: ALOES. ANIMAL: CENTAUR, HIPPOGRIFF, HORSE, DOG.

CAPTION: All living things being made from one double helix, perhaps the only true "Information Gathering and Utilizing System" is DNA itself.

CAPTION: According to Narby's Cosmic Serpent, shamanic rainforest rock-art resembles double helixes, chromosome pairings, and DNA in spread-out form.

CAPTION: Humans have 23 chromosome pairs, 23 being the snake's magical number.

PROMETHEA: AS SYMBOLS, MOONS AND SNAKES HAVE AFFINITY.

PROMETHEA: THE PHALLIC SERPENT REPRESENTS MALE FERTILITY, AS DOES KABBALA'S SECOND SPHERE, CHOKMAH. THE MOON, FEMALE FERTILTY, RELATES TO SPHERE THREE, BINAH.

PROMETHEA: ALL CREATION SPRINGS FROM THEIR SEXUAL UNION.

CAPTION: 11 TAROT PATH: THE FOOL. ELEMENT: AIR. COLOR: SKY-BLUE. JEWEL: TOPAZ, CHALCEDONY. PLANT: ASPEN. PERFUME: GALBANUM. ANIMAL: EAGLE OR MAN.

CAPTION: In human terms, the snake or phallus symbolizes the Will, whilst the Moon represents our female, receptive Imagination. Thus creativity results from union between Will and Imagination.

CAPTION: In cosmological terms, some Quantum cosmologists suggest that the best description of the Universe's initial inflation or explosion is "Chokmah-Binah", the same reproductive union.

PROMETHEA: SNAKES SOMETIMES SYMBOLIZE MAGIC'S UNDERWORLD FORCES, THOSE OF HUMANITY'S UNCONSCIOUS, PORTRAYED BY PSYCHOLOGIST CARL JUNG AS A PRIMITIVE CAVE.

PROMETHEA: ANOTHER MAGICAL SYMBOL OF THE UNDERWORLD OR UNCONSCIOUS IS THE MOON; OUR SILVERY, IMMATERIAL IMAGINATION.

CAPTION: 12 TAROT PATH: MAGICIAN OR JUGGLER. PLANET: MERCURY. COLOR: PURPLE. JEWEL: OPAL, AGATE. PLANT: VERVAIN, HERB MERCURY, MARJOLANE, PALM. PERFUME: MASTIC, WHITE SANDAL, MACE. ANIMAL: APE, SWALLOW, IBIS.

CAPTION: CARL GUSTAV JUNG 1875-1961

CAPTION: According to Robert Anton Wilson, on one day in the 1920s, Aleister Crowley, Albert Einstein, and James Joyce were all in Carl Jung's Vienna and could (conceivably) have met.

CAPTION: Jung's theories, viewed by mentor Sigmund Freud as dangerously close to Occultism, suggested gods were archetypes recurring throughout the Mass Unconscious, another kind of Immateria.

CAPTION: 26 TAROT PATH: THE DEVIL. ZODIAC SIGN: CAPRICORN. COLOR: BLACK. JEWEL: BLACK DIAMOND. PLANT: INDIAN HEMP, ORCHIS ROOT, THISTLE. PERFUME: MUSK, CIVET, ALL "SATURNINE" PERFUMES. ANIMAL: GOAT, ASS.

PROMETHEA: SNAKES, ACCORDING TO ROBERT GRAVES, ARE ASSOCIATED WITH THE SPERM-SHAPED PSILOCYBIN MUSHROOM, ONE OF SHAMANISM'S EARLIEST PSYCHEDELIC TOOLS.

PROMETHEA: PERHAPS IN CONNECTION, MEDIEVAL ALCHEMISTS LABELLED PSILOCYBIN WITH THE NAME OF SNAKE-ASSOCIATED MEDICINE GOD, AESCLEPIUS.

CAPTION: Mushrooms are a fungus, recently discovered to contain collagen, a substance found in animal life but not in vegetable matter, implying some biological connection between animals, including humans, and fungi.

CAPTION: For whatever reason, certain mushrooms have startling effects upon consciousness, and, some have suggested, may have accelerated humanity's mental and cultural development.

PROMETHEA: THE PSYCHEDELIC EXPERIENCE SEEMS CENTRAL TO THE MAGICAL WORLDVIEW.

PROMETHEA: ROBERT GRAVES ARGUES CONVINCINGLY THAT FABLED DIVINE POTIONS SUCH AS NECTAR AND AMBROSIA CONTAINED MUSHROOMS, AS, ALLEGEDLY, DID SOMA, HINDU MYTHOLOGY'S "DRINK OF THE GODS."

CAPTION: Grave suggests that in recipes for Nectar, Ambrosia, and Demeter's Eleusinian potion, the initial letters of listed ingredients spell mukades, Greek for mushroom, and it's diminutives muka and muk.

CAPTION: 22 TAROT PATH: JUSTICE, OR ADJUSTMENT. ZODIAC SIGN: LIBRA. COLOR: BLUE. JEWEL: EMERALD. PLANT: ALOE. PERFUME: GALBANUM. ANIMAL: ELEPHANT.

CAPTION: While sometimes indicating any psychdelic drink, even hashish preparations, Soma specifically refers to Amanita, the spotted Fly Agaric mushroom familiar from fairy tales.

PROMETHEA: CONVENTIONAL RELIGION ECHOES THIS PSYCHEDELIC SENSORY OVERLOAD WITH ITS MUSIC, INCANTATIONS, ART, INCENSE, AND STAINED GLASS WINDOW "LIGHT SHOWS."

PROMETHEA: YET RELIGION, BASED ON "SHARED BELIEF," RESEMBLES SCIENCE MORE THAN IT RESEMBLES MAGIC.

CAPTION: * CLAUDIO  MONTEVERDI  1567 - 1643 *

CAPTION: Opera, as developed by practicing alchemists, such as Monteverdi, attempted to magically alter consciousness by incorporating music, words, costume and dance to similarly overwhelm the senses.

CAPTION: Sharing the same Latin root as "ligature", "religion" means "tied together in one belief," not necessarily spiritual. Scientific and political dogmas, therefore, are also technically religions.

CAPTION: 7 SEPHIRA: NETZACH, OR VICTORY. PLANET: VENUS. GODDESSES: VENUS, APHRODITE, HATHOR, FREYA, NIKÉ (WINGED VICTORY). DAY OF THE WEEK: FRIDAY. COLOR: EMERALD. JEWEL: EMERALD. PLANT: ROSE. PERFUME: BENZOIN, ROSE, RED SANDAL. ANIMAL: LYNX.

CAPTION: 6 SEPHIRA: TIPHERETH, OR HARMONY/BEAUTY. PLANET: THE SUN. GODS: APOLLO, OSIRIS, JESUS, ATTIS, BALDER, ALL SOLAR OR RESURRECTED GODS. DAY OF THE WEEK: SUNDAY. COLOR: YELLOW/GOLD. JEWEL: TOPAZ, YELLOW DIAMOND. PLANT: BAY, ACACIA, VINE, LAUREL. PERFUME: OLIBANUM. ANIMAL: PHOENIX, LION, CHILD.

CAPTION: Troubled by consciousness, Science regards Mind as an hallucination of our nervous system, of biology, solidly founded on chemistry and, ultimately, hard physics.

CAPTION: However, as Harold Morowitz states in Rediscovering the Mind, physics rests upn quantum mechanics, which Werner Heisenberg asserted as inseparable from the influence of the observing human mind.

CAPTION: WERNER KARL HEISENBERG  1901-1976

PROMETHEA: SCIENCE, HOWEVER, DESPITE HAVING EVOLVED FROM ALCHEMY, IS BASED UPON RELIABLY REPEATABLE PHENOMENA, AND THEREFORE CANNOT DISCUSS EVEN EVERYDAY CONSCIOUSNESS...

PROMETHEA: ...MUCH LESS THE EXPLODING, PSYCHEDELIC EXPERIENCE OF MAGIC, OF OUR HUMAN PSYCHE, OF OUR SOUL.

PROMETHEA: CONSCIOUSNESS, EVEN AT THESE ECSTATIC EXTREMES, ARISES FROM LANGUAGE, AS DO RELIGION AND TECHNOLOGY (MEANING SIMPLY "WRITINGS ABOUT A BODY OF KNOWLEDGE").

PROMETHEA: THUS, ALL THESE THINGS ARE GOVERNED BY LANGUAGE GODS LIKE THOTH OR HERMES.

CAPTION: Kabbala's descending energy is formless until it reaches Hod, the eighth sphere of the writing-gods, where it is dressed in imagery and language.

CAPTION: Hod, governing science, magic and language, is associated with messenger god Hermes, scribe god Thoth, and Odin, who endured hanging to become initiated in the magical Runic language.

CAPTION: 23 TAROT PATH: THE HANGED MAN. ELEMENT: WATER. COLOR: SEA GREEN. JEWEL: BERYL OR AQUAMARINE. PLANT: LOTUS, ALL WATER PLANTS. PERFUME: ONYCHA, MYRRH. ANIMAL: EAGLE, SCORPION, SNAKE.

CAPTION: That certain arrangements of words affect consciousness is evident in Douglas Hofstadter's essay on nonsense poetry in Metamagical Themas; the drug-influenced lyrics of the mid-1960s; and Alchemy's concept of altering consciousness using a poetic "Language of the Birds."

CAPTION: 27 TAROT PATH: THE TOWER. PLANET: MARS. COLOR: RED. JEWEL: RUBY, ANY RED STONE. PLANT: RUE, ABSINTHE. PERFUME: PEPPER, DRAGON'S BLOOD, ALL HOT, PUNGENT ODORS. ANIMAL: BEAR, HORSE, WOLF.

CAPTION: Magic-god Thoth allegedly derived human speech from the speech of birds.

PROMETHEA: BOTH THOTH AND HERMES HAVE SNAKES AS SACRED ANIMALS, WITH SERPENTINE LINGUISTICS ALSO IMPLIED IN THE RAINFOREST SHAMAN'S ART OF "LANGUAGE-TWISTING-TWISTING."

PROMETHEA: WE CONJURED ALL REALITY WITH INTRICATE, SNAKING WORDS; WITH SILVER-TONGUED MAGIC.

PROMETHEA: CONSCIOUSNESS, ART AND LANGUAGE HAPPEN WHEN MATERIAL ORGANISMS CONNECT WITH IMMATERIAL FANCIES, WHEN EARTHLY LIFE'S DNA SERPENT DANCES WITH IMAGINATION'S LUNAR SPIRIT.

PROMETHEA: AS WITH TAROT'S FINAL 32ND PATH, THEIR DANCE CREATES REALITY, CREATES OUR UNIVERSE.

CAPTION: 10 SEPHIRA: MALKUTH, OR THE KINGDOM. PLANET: EARTH. GODS/GODDESSES: PERSEPHONE, DEMETER, CERES, GEB, NEPHTHYS, ALL EARTH GODS. COLORS: CITRINE, OLIVE, RUSSET AND BLACK. JEWEL: ROCK CRYSTAL. PLANT: IVY, WILLOW, LILY, ALL GRAINS. PERFUME: DITTANY OF CRETE. ANIMAL: SPHINX.

CAPTION: Creative union between animal male forces and lunar female energies seems universal; animalistic Pan rapes lunar Selene; Crowley's lunar whore/mother-goddess Babalon straddles a "Great Beast," sometimes called "that old serpent."

CAPTION: Even Catholic iconography sometimes portrays the Madonna before a crescent moon, a serpent beneath her feet, symbolizing the immaculate conception.

PROMETHEA: YOUR CONSCIOUSNESS OF THIS CURRENT WORK DEPENDS UPON WORDS, IMAGES, THE VISUAL LANGUAGE COMPRISING IT.

PROMETHEA: AS READERS, YOU ARE PHYSICAL BEINGS ENGAGING IN A DNA SNAKE-DANCE WITH ME, A FICTION, YOUR IMMATERIAL, LUNAR IMAGINATION.

CAPTION: To the Old Testament's Creator God, or to any newborn infant, the Universe and themselves are initially perceived as one indivisible thing.

CAPTION: Naming things, God, or the infant, separates itself from everything else with language, divides earth from sky, fish from fowl, and thus creates and constructs the diverse Universe around them.

CAPTION: 14 TAROT PATH: THE EMPRESS. PLANET: VENUS. COLOR: SKY BLUE. JEWEL: EMERALD, TURQUOISE. PLANT: ROSE, MYRTLE, CLOVER. PERFUME: SANDALWOOD, MYRTLE, ALL SOFT AND VOLUPTUOUS ODORS. ANIMAL: SPARROW, DOVE, SWAN.

ON BLOCK: A

ON BLOCK: B

ON BLOCK: C

CAPTION: Light, the rush of photons, is our Universe's foremost carrier of information. Describing spiritual information, transmitted by metaphorical light, we talk of becoming illuminated, either as individuals or as a species.

PROMETHEA: PROMETHEA, LIKE EVERYTHING YOU'VE EVER READ OR WITNESSED, IS MADE ONLY OF LIGHT: THE REFLECTED LIGHT OF THIS POSTER-COMIC PLAYING OVER YOUR EYE.

PROMETHEA: THE LIGHT OF IMAGINATION AND PLAY OF MEANING ACROSS YOUR MIND.

CAPTION: Some cultures, believing that we know everything already but have forgotten that we do, refer to illumination as "loss of forgetfulness."

CAPTION: 31 TAROT PATH: THE ANGEL, LAST JUDGMENT, OR ÆON. ELEMENT: FIRE. COLOR: VERMILLION. JEWEL: FIRE OPAL. PLANT: RED POPPY, NETTLE, HIBISCUS. PERFUME: OLIBANUM, ALL FIERY ODORS. ANIMAL: LION.

CAPTION: The word, or Logos, is our original, most sophisticated technology, still unsurpassed, requiring no batteries, little maintenance, and, with only twenty-six squiggles, mastering the Universe.

CAPTION: All alphabets, then, are magical alphabets, from English, Hebrew, or Greek to Austin Spare's "Alphabet of Desire" to the mysterious Runic alphabet coveted by Odin.

CAPTION: 19 TAROT PATH: STRENGTH, OR LUST. ZODIAC SIGN: LEO. COLOR: DEEP PURPLE. JEWEL: CAT'S EYE. PLANT: SUNFLOWER. PERFUME: OLIBANUM. ANIMAL: LION.

CAPTION: AUSTIN OSMAN SPARE 1886-1956

PROMETHEA: USING LANGUAGE, WE DECODE EXISTENCE, MAKE IT LUCID, CAST LIGHT UPON IT.

PROMETHEA: THESE MARKS ON PAPER THAT YOU ARE READING ARE A PROGRAM, RUNNING ON THE HIGH-REZ SOFTWARE OF THE HUMAN MIND AND IT'S IMAGINATION.

PROMETHEA: IT'S ALSO APPROPRIATE THAT I'M TALKING TO YOU THROUGH THE MEDIUM OF A COMIC-STRIP STORY.

PROMETHEA: IDEOGRAMS AND HIEROGLYPHIC PICTURE STORIES WERE OUR EARLIEST WRITTEN LANGUAGE, HOW WE RECORDED OUR EXPLOITS AND OUR FABULOUS IMAGININGS.

CAPTION: 2 SEPHIRA: CHOKMAH, OR WISDOM. PLANET: THE ZODIAC. GODS: PAN, PRIAPUS, THE HOLY GHOST, GLYCON, ALL PHALLIC DEITIES. COLOR: GREY. JEWEL: STAR RUBY, TURQUOISE. PLANT: AMARANTH. PERFUME: MUSK. ANIMAL: MAN.

CAPTION: Pentagon studies in the 1980s demonstrated that comic strip narrative is still the best way of conveying understandable and retainable information.

CAPTION: Words being the currency of our verbal "left" brain, and images that of our pre-verbal "right" brain, perhaps comic strip reading prompts both halves to work in unison?

PROMETHEA: WE CREATED FANTASIES THEN STRUGGLED TO REALIZE THEM. EVERYTHING AROUND YOU RIGHT NOW ORIGINATED IN SOMEONE'S MIND.

PROMETHEA: CREATING GODS, GODDESSES, HEROES AND HEROINES, WE TRIED TO BECOME LIKE THEM, EXTENDING OURSELVES THROUGH SHEER IMAGINATION.

CAPTION: Classical god-statues were intended for meditation purposes rather than worship, so that by understanding a god's qualities, we might reproduce them more fully in ourselves.

CAPTION: If gods are transcendent ideas, then the idea of a god IS a god. Divine images attempted to raise human consciousness using the power of art.

CAPTION: 3 SEPHIRA: BINAH, OR UNDERSTANDING. PLANET: SATURN. GODDESSES: THE MADONNA, EXPECIALLY THE BLACK MADONNA, ISIS, HECATE, BABALON, SELENE. DAY OF THE WEEK: SATURDAY. COLOR: BLACK. JEWEL: STAR SAPPHIRE, PEARL. PLANT: CYPRESS, OPIUM POPPY. PERFUME: MYRRH, CIVET. ANIMAL: WOMAN.

PROMETHEA: IMAGINATION CAN TRANSFORM US. YESOD, THE LUNAR SPHERE OF IMAGINATION, IS THE FOUNDATION ON WHICH OUR SPIRITUAL LIFE RESTS.

PROMETHEA: IMAGINATION ARISES OUT OF CONSCIOUSNESS, WHICH ITSELF BLOSSOMS FROM HOD, THE MERCURIAL, MAGICAL SPHERE OF LANGUAGE.

IN BACKGROUND: 1  3  2  5  4  6  8 E=mc2 1 * 1 + 1 + 1  7  9  10

CAPTION: Kabbala is a venerable, originally verbal tradition, organizing the entirety of Hebrew thought, with its alphabet and numbers, into one knowledge system, represented by the Tree of Life glyph.

CAPTION: Hod and Yesod are of special interest to the magician or shaman, being readily accessible through dreams, imaginative ritual meditations, or psychedelic drugs.

CAPTION: 18 TAROT PATH: THE CHARIOT. ZODIAC SIGN: CANCER. COLOR: MAROON. JEWEL: AMBER. PLANT: LOTUS. PERFUME: ONYCHA. ANIMAL: CRAB, TURTLE, SPHINX.

PROMETHEA: USING LANGUAGE, IMAGINATION AND WILL, WE CREATE REALITY, MOMENT BY MOMENT, WEAVING CONCEPTS AND SENSATIONS, LIGHT AND SOUND, ON THE LOOM OF OUR CONSCIOUSNESS...

PROMETHEA: ...JUST AS YOU'RE DOING NOW, READING THIS FINAL EPISODE OF PROMETHEA.

CAPTION: Will, situated above intellect and emotion at the solar sphere, Tiphereth, is our highest self, our soul, the gold Alchemists sought. It's the Christ and Apollo in us, our perfect fulcrum of spiritual harmony.

CAPTION: In The Sacred Mushroom and the Cross, John Allegro suggests that solar Christianity derives from psilocybin cult.

CAPTION: 30 TAROT PATH: THE SUN. PLANET: THE SUN. COLOR: GOLD-YELLOW. JEWEL: CRYSOLETH. PLANT: SUNFLOWER, LAUREL, HELIOTROPE. PERFUME: OLIBANUM, CINNAMON, ALL "GLORIOUS" ODORS. ANIMAL: LION, SPARROWHAWK.

CAPTION: Visionary Emanuel Swedenborg stated, "Angels know nothing of Time." The solar consciousness of Tiphereth is eternal, like Einstein's Spacetime, or Joyce's eternity-embracing single day.

CAPTION: Both lunar and serpentine, Promethea represents those fertile forces coupling within us, whereby we parthenogenetically conceive and birth the shining, redeeming child of our own sacred Will.

CAPTION: SOPHIA BANGS, PROMETHEA 1999-2004

CATION: 15 TAROT PATH: THE EMPEROR. ZODIAC SIGN: ARIES. COLOR: RED. JEWEL: RUBY. PLANT: TIGER LILY, GERANIUM. PERFUME: DRAGON'S BLOOD. ANIMAL: RAM, OWL.

PROMETHEA: I'VE ENJOYED OUR DANCE. YOU WERE THE PERFECT PARTNER, AND I'M GOING TO MISS YOU.

PROMETHEA: BUT SPACETIME IS ETERNAL, WITH EVERYTHING IN IT.

PROMETHEA: AND YOU AND ME ARE ALWAYS HERE, ALWAYS NOW.

PROMETHEA: YOU AND ME ARE FOREVER.